Guide to the Bellingham Woman's Music Club records 1917-1972
Western Washington University, Heritage Resources
Bellingham Woman's Music Club records
1917-1972
Western Washington University Heritage Resources Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7747 Email: heritage.resources@wwu.edu http://library.wwu.edu/heritageresources
XOE_CPNWS0051bwmusicclub
Bellingham Woman's Music Club
4 linear feet.
The records of the Bellingham Woman’s Music Club, spanning 1917-1972, document its members’ contribution to Bellingham’s cultural development. The collection includes minute books, yearbooks, scrapbooks, and the club’s constitution.
The Bellingham Woman’s Music Club was organized February 22, 1916. It provided a forum for its members to perform musical selections and it organized performances by its members and professionals from elsewhere for the benefit of the public. The club was composed of both active members, who performed, and associate members, who were permitted to attend the meetings. By 1924 it was federated with the Washington State Federation of Music Clubs and the National Federation of Music Clubs. The club endeavored to involve itself in the community. Some of these efforts included providing concerts, offering scholarships for membership, and a large donation of record albums to the public library with station KVOS and Western Washington College of Education.
The records of the Bellingham Woman’s Music Club, spanning 1917-1972, document its members’ contribution to Bellingham’s cultural development. The collection includes minute books, yearbooks, scrapbooks, and the club’s constitution.
Minute books contain summaries of meetings, musical selections performed by the active members at the meetings, newspaper clippings, correspondence, and printed programs of the performances and activities the club sponsored. The minute books begin in 1917 and end in 1968. The yearbooks record the officers of the club and include the events planned for the year. Some of the yearbooks are missing, but can be found pasted into either the minute books or the scrapbooks. The scrapbooks include printed programs of musical performances and social activities, photographs, newspaper clippings, and correspondence. The scrapbooks date from 1941 to 1972; however, the scrapbook that covers the 1950s was never organized.
The Bellingham Woman's Music Club records are organized in accordance with the following series and subseries arrangement:
Series I: Administrative Records, 1917-1968
Sub-series 1. Minute Books, 1917-1968
Sub-series 2. Club Constitutions, 1923-1950
Sub-series 3. Member Sponsorship Cards, 1960-1961
Series II: Yearbooks, 1917-1972
Series III: Scrapbooks, 1941-1972
The collection is open to the public.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Bellingham Woman's Music Club - Archives.
Music -- Societies, etc -- Washington (State) -- Bellingham -- History -- Sources.; Women -- Societies and clubs -- Washington (State) -- Bellingham -- History -- Sources.; Scrapbooks -- Washington (State).
Arts and Humanities; Women; Performing Arts
Scrapbooks -- Washington (State).
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Administrative Records, 1917-1968; Series I
  - Minute Books, 1917-1968; Subseries 1
    - Minute Book, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Minute Book, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Minute Book, 1920-1923 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Minute Book, 1923-1925 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Minute Book, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Minute Book, 1928-1935 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Minute Book, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Minute Book, 1942-1949 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Minute Book, 1949-1954 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Minute Book, 1954-1959 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Minute Book, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Minute Book, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Club Constitutions, 1923-1950; Subseries 2
    - Constitutions, 1923-1950 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Member Sponsorship Cards, 1960-1961; Subseries 3
    Additional cards may be found in later volumes of the minute books.
    - Membership sponsorship cards, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 2/3)
- Yearbooks, 1917-1972; Series II
  - Yearbooks, 1917-1920 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Yearbooks, 1920-1930 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Yearbooks, 1930-1940 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Yearbooks, 1940-1949 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Yearbooks, 1950-1960 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Yearbooks, 1961-1970 (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Yearbooks, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 2/10)
- Scrapbooks, 1941-1972; Series III
  - Scrapbooks, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Scrapbooks, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Scrapbooks, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Scrapbooks, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Scrapbooks, 1952-1964 (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Scrapbooks, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Scrapbooks, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Scrapbooks, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Scrapbooks, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Scrapbooks, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 6/4)